{
    "id": "89b9c653401d449bab41f302d109453d",
    "title": "Pronouns Exercise For Beginners",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "bd4f44087056426b9482cbe5a8dd89a7",
            "title": "Pronouns exercise for beginners",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Peter's mother went to the market. He went with ..................................",
                    "description": "We need an object pronoun (him, her, them, us) after a preposition. Note that the pronouns you and it have the same subject and object forms. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "she",
                        "her"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The children are playing in the park. ............................. are having a great time.",
                    "description": "We need a plural pronoun to refer to a plural noun. He and she are singular.",
                    "answers": [
                        "He",
                        "She",
                        "They"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Tom is running to catch the ball. ........................ is wearing a blue shirt.",
                    "description": "We need a subject pronoun here. He is the subject form. Him is the object form. His is the possessive form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "He",
                        "Him",
                        "His"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Reddy Fox saw a monster. The monster frightened .......................",
                    "description": "A pronoun used as the object should be in its object form. He is the subject form and him is the object form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "he",
                        "him"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don't eat this mango. ............................ is rotten.",
                    "description": "We use 'it' to refer to things and animals.",
                    "answers": [
                        "It",
                        "Its"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The students are making a lot of noise. Please ask ........................... to keep quiet.",
                    "description": "Them is the object form of they.",
                    "answers": [
                        "they",
                        "them",
                        "their"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "My brother likes storybooks. I bought this for ........................",
                    "description": "The pronoun used as the object of a preposition should be in its object form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "he",
                        "him"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Nancy is a good girl. Everybody likes .........................",
                    "description": "Here the pronoun is the object of the verb 'likes', so it should be in its object form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "she",
                        "her"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": ".............................. are going to the cinema. Do you want to come with ..........................?",
                    "description": "Here the first pronoun is the subject and the second pronoun is the object. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "We, us",
                        "We, we",
                        "Us, we"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don't eat this mango. I will get a good one for ....................",
                    "description": "The pronoun 'you' has the same object and subject forms.",
                    "answers": [
                        "you",
                        "your",
                        "yours"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "That dog is ............................ This is .........................",
                    "description": "His is the possessive form of he. Likewise, ours are the possessive form of we. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "him, us",
                        "his, our",
                        "his, ours"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "My daughters like to watch Disney films. This CD is for ..........................",
                    "description": "A pronoun used as the object of a preposition should be in its object form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "they",
                        "them",
                        "their"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}